Mike Trumbell

About

I'm a technologist from Chicago, IL with over 10 years of experience building web and mobile apps, REST APIs, and back office enterprise solutions. I bring a unique perspective to a development team and my diverse background allows me to solve a wide range of difficult problems through software.

Experience

Software Engineering Lead, Vela/OptionsCity, Chicago, IL, 2015-Present

- Led the successful migration from a legacy Windows app to an EmberJS multi-platform app packaged in Electron. The project involved months of planning, leading a team of devs, replacing dozens of features to support hundreds of existing customers.
- Built a multi-device mobile application for Android and iOS that reused many of our web components.
- Mentored 2 EmberJS and Django developers in building and maintaining 5 different production applications and assisted them with organizing quarterly goals.
- Managed weekly releases to our client applications including writing release notes and notifying high profile customers of large changes.
- Built several AP features in Scala including a new permission framework which closely resembles the Django permissions model
- Successfully satisfied a CME market data entitlements audit by organizing years worth of subscription data from both the City and Metro platforms

Software Engineer, OptionsCity, Chicago, IL, 2011-2015

- Designed a data schema using Django, South, MySQL and MongoDB to house all of the company's customer data, trading history and subscription data.
- In Django and Javascript, built a CRM application that automated dozens of processes for our sales, account management, support and DevOps teams.
- Interviewed staff to design features to quickly turn around customer requests and help to streamline on boarding.
- Designed and implemented an externally facing customer portal in Django and Javascript to allow Risk Admins to manage trader risk limits.
- Designed and implemented a framework in Django and Celery to allow support staff to easily configure complex customer reporting jobs interfacing with hundreds of software nodes and databases.

Software Engineer, TradeForecaster, Chicago, IL, 2009-2011

- Added features to the Django and JavaScript application for administering (software updates, instance recycling, database migrations and reports, etc.) trading platforms.
- Streamlined commercial trader signup process to allow for quicker access to our trading platform by gathering requirements, interview customers and replacing paper processes with web forms.
- Administered all database migrations using Django and South and organized and scheduled them per trading exchange's maintenance windows.
- Built custom reports and tools for traders to manage their positions, load balance trading strategies per instance, separate network traffic for optimal performance and to help automate dozens of other day-to-day operations.

Application Support Engineer, TradeForecaster, Chicago, IL, 2008-2009

- Built and maintained hardware for low-latency, high-performance trading system.
- · Led classes at the CBOT about how to use our platform.
- Administered farm of servers and ensured application health through monitoring in Nagios, Hyperic and Smokeping.
- Fielded support calls from professional traders and answered questions on a wide range of topics including position information, order status, latency and computer performance.
- Wrote scripts in Python and Bash to automate the management and debugging of our production applications.

Skills

Languages and Frameworks

- JavaScript including EmberJS and JQuery
- · Python and the Django framework
- Scala and the Play framework

Databases and Cloud

- · MySQL and PostGreSQL
- MongoDB
- · Google Firebase
- AWS

Education

Central Michigan University - BS in Management Information Systems, 2006